Ronnel Sanchez

UI/UX Designer and Front-End Developer

Email: ronnel.sanchez@gmail.com

Mobile: (63) 927 2197146

Skype: ronnel.sanchez@outlook.com

About Me

Having the expertise on User Experiense, I manage to produce User Centered Design website and software. I design base user perspective with clear understanding on system and business side. Also doing Front-End Developement, i merge the UX Guidlines on producing the User Interface with the current technology development like; Responsive Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility and UX Design. Enjoy learning new technology, design tools, programming language and UI/UXguidelines technic which I believe is the core of every project i do.

Work Experience

UI/UX Designer and Front-End Developer | Dec 2017 - Present

Ducatus Global – Singapore (Philippine Base)

- Key designer for Ducatus Customer console site redesign
- Deliver UI/UX design for Ducatus internal and external apps
- Create design prototype, high fidelity mock-ups, and visual design
- Create user flow, wireframes, personas, storyboards, process flow and interaction design

UI/UX Designer and Front-End Developer | Dec 2012 – Dec 2017

Trend Micro Philippines - Ortigas, Pasig City

- Doing Business Process Analysis roles like, studying business process, presenting new ideas to improve the business flow, producing mock-ups and prototypes, checking the development of the projects and handling the sustain and new request.
- Conducting User Experience research which include observation, interview, A/B testing, mouse flow and heat maps.

- Present wireframes, user interaction and process flows ideas to stakeholders using Adobe Photoshop, InVision and Axure.
- Created low to high fidelity prototypes for web or mobile applications using HTML, CSS and Sass. Also with JavaScript frameworks like Bootstrap, jQuery, Angular.js, and Vue.js.
- Produced responsive and cross browser design which fits to business and user requirements.
- Created User Centered Design into web/mobile site pages, and native mobile app design.
- Created email newsletters or EDM design and other graphics like logos, icons, motion graphics, video presentations and infographics.

Graphical User Interface Designer | Sept 2012 - Oct 2012

Job and Esther Technologies - Alabang, Muntinlupa City

- Create graphical user interfaces (GUIs) for a variety of software products, including (but not limited to) mobile, web, desktop, games, enterprise applications, communication systems and others.
- Collaborate in the writing and maintenance of a GUI style guide.
- Work with our marketing team to design, edit, and maintain online and offline marketing promotional materials like brochures, banners, posters, logos & print ads.
- Work closely with product managers and software developers to define and design an optimal user experience, user interaction model, workflow and information architecture.
- Frame out website designs and provide detail and direction to development staff to implement design using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Create mockup designs when needed using appropriate tools and design programs.

UI Designer and Developer | Dec 2010 - Sept 2012

Coding Solution Information Technology - Pagsanjan, Laguna

- Produced websites and PC software design that fits to Business requirements.
- Work as front-end developer for Website and Mobile apps.
- Work closely with team lead and back-end developer to produce mock-ups, mark-ups and prototypes.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology | 2008 – 2012

AMA Computer University - Santa Cruz Laguna, Philippines

Website Links

Behance https://www.behance.net/ronnelsanchez

Dribbble https://dribbble.com/ronnelsanchez

LinkedIn https://ph.linkedin.com/in/ronnelsanchez

GitHub ronnelsanchez.github.io/Resume

Personal Information

Name Ronnel Joan R. Sanchez

Birth Day April 12, 1992

Location Philippines

Mobile (+63) 9272197146

Email ronnel.sanchez@gmail.com

Skills

Professional

User Interface Design

User Experience

Front-End Development

Agile Methodology

Cross browser development

Visual Design

Graphic Design

Motion Graphics

Prototyping

Wire Framing

Technical

HTML / HTML 5

CSS / CSS 3

JavaScript / JQuery

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Illustrator

InVision

Axure

Reference

Myn Reyes | User Experience Team Lead
Trend Micro Inc. Philippines
normyn.reyes@gmail.com

Miko Mojica | Marketing Liaison Asian Development Bank miko jazmine@yahoo.com